Kenneth Schaefer

Software Engineer

Personal Info

EMAIL

kenneth.schaefer0@gmail.com

PHONE

317-361-2543

LINKEDIN

https://linkedin.com/in/parzid

og

Software / Languages



Hobbies / Interests

My Wife and Three Boys Learning Programming Languages Learning New Software Figuring Out How Things Work Being Challenged A lifelong student and high-performing software engineer with a passion for all things IT and over 15 years of experience impacting positive outcomes through team building and attention to detail with 3 years in software development.

Projects

2022-11 Sole Full Stack Developer

WF Self Storage

- This is a professional project that aids self-storage customers with information and allows the facility workers to easily update the website with new unit sizes and prices.
- Implemented a scalable, single-page application with dynamic loading and quick response times.
- Created and integrated a hosted PostgreSQL server on Heroku while maintaining an operationally ready data flow for current users.
- Implemented everything from a wire diagram that was approved by the customer to style updates before obtaining final production approval.

2022-10 Front End Developer

Hello Kitchen

- Aids a user in selecting meals and purchasing the necessary ingredients to make those meals.
- Implemented a simple, feature-rich single-page application model with nested routes for quick, concise load times with a mobile-friendly view.
- Applied an integration with the Amazon Fresh Testing API to allow users to export their shopping list to order items through the Amazon Fresh website.
- Integrated with Google Maps / Places API that allows users to quickly and efficiently search for the nearest grocery stores to buy the ingredients from their shopping list.

2022-08 Full Stack Developer

Grace Adopter

- Developed a pet adoption agency that aims to help lonely pets find their FurEver Home.
- Solidified parts of my knowledge in using React/Redux and Toolkit as middleware for sending and receiving data from a database.
- Created and integrated a hosted PostgreSQL server on Heroku while maintaining an operationally ready data flow for current users.
- Strengthened my understanding of the importance of having a proper Git workflow to maintain application uptime and Continuous Integration / Continuous Deployment methodology.

Work History

2021-09 - present

IT Consultant / General Manager

Donald Jones Consulting, Wichita Falls

- Managed a process re-engineering project to improve and consolidate end-to-end service processes.
- Restructured communication flow among 28 facilities and cut down paperwork by 45%.
- Controlled the release of proprietary information by organizing and developing secure information systems.
- Analyzed and adjusted work procedures for the chief of

- operations that maximized production efficiency by 32%.
- Planned, set and implemented facility goals while maintaining budget standards which led to a 120% increase in facility utilization.

2020-02 - 2020-10

Hospital Security Officer

Trinity Executive Services, Indianapolis

- Implemented effective deescalation techniques that lowered the number of physical confrontations by 28% during the height of the COVID pandemic.
- Coordinated numerous security protocols to comply with both HIPAA and Joint Commission standards while protecting the doctors, nurses and patients of 5 separate facilities.
- Controlled the release of proprietary information by organizing and developing 5 secure information systems.
- Assessed the development and effectiveness of 15 subordinates while cultivating the strengths of individuals within the team.

2018-01 - 2020-01

Lead Commercial Foreman

G3, Inc, Indianapolis

- Planned, scheduled and assigned work for optimal distribution, staffing and production of up to 3 job sites simultaneously; consistently achieved deadlines, and quality control goals while producing quality intertrade relations.
- Negotiated general contracts, purchase orders and subcontract agreements with clients and subcontractors.
- Supervised crews of up to 10 carpenters, journeymen, drywall hangers, and general labor personnel.
- Inspected work in progress to ensure quality and conformity to contract and drawing specifications in accordance with state and federal guidelines.

2010-12 - 2018-01

Sergeant / Division Lead

United States Marine Corps

- Held a Top Secret security clearance from 2012 2018.
- Overcame seemingly insurmountable odds to attain daily operational readiness on 2 separate occasions. As a result, was awarded the Navy and Marine Corps Achievement medal on both occasions.
- Re-engineered the technical documentation process for the most extensive program in military aviation in order to improve document access and storage by 86% while removing the time needed for the project management by 79%.
- Cultivated an environment that encourages organizational readiness and individual mental health awareness.
- Supervised and commanded maintenance teams of up to 65
 Marines in high-stress combat situations
 while maintaining a professional, combat-ready squadron
 of F/A-18 and F-35 fighter jets.

Degrees / Certifications

2022-06 - 2022-10 Software Engineering, Certification

Fullstack Academy, New York, NY

2022-01 - 2023-03 Mechanical Engineering, Associate's of Science

Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University, Daytona Beach, FL